简单来说, 行凶手法
和杀害劳拉的一样.
The short answer is, this is the work
of the same ghoul who killed Laura.
还有更疯狂的.
More fan mail.
这是在马蒂指甲下发现的
字母『O』.
The letter O
under Maddy's ring fingernail.
她右手上还有
些羽绒毛线.
There were strands of fur
clutched in her right hand.
- 是什么毛?
- 白狐貍的.
- What kind of fur?
- White fox.
毛线是用甲醛制过的
动物标本，填塞用的.
The strands were laced with
formaldehyde. A dead animal, stuffed.
l'll make phone calls. Leland will know
how to get a hold of Maddy's family.
我去打几个电话. 利兰该知道
怎样联系马蒂的家人.
Harry, don't make any calls.
哈里, 先别急着打电话.
- 我需要24小时.
- 干什么用?
- l need 24 hours.
- For what?
To finish this.
去了结这事儿.
库珀.
Cooper.
依我看...
ln observation...
...l don't know where this is headed.
...这个案子不知道什么时候才能破.
But the only one of us
with coordinates
但我们唯一
对此能达成共识的
for this destination and its hardware
is you.
就是你的确有
破案的实力.
Go on whatever vision quest
you require.
无论怎样
继续去追随你的先验吧.
Stand on the rim of the volcano,
stand alone and do your dance.
独自站在火山口,
跳你的祈求祭祀舞.
Just find this beast
before he takes another bite.
只不过，最好在下一个受害者出现之前
把这只野兽找出来.
God help me,
l don't know where to start.
神助我吧,
我也搞不清路向何方了.
你已经上路了.
你不需要知道它向何方.
You're on the path.
You don't need to know where it leads.
只管跟着它走就是了.
Just follow.
l thought you'd never get here.
我以为你不会来了.
l went for a ride this morning.
我今早开车去兜风了.
God, the engine sounded like
a thousand people singing.
天啊, 引擎的声音美妙的就像
千人大合唱.
- 那他们在唱什么呢?
- 你觉得呢?
- What were they singing about?
- What do you think?
唱昨晚吗?
我想是在唱昨晚.
Last night?
l could sing about last night.
我有东西给你.
l got something for you.
Open it.
打开吧.
噢, 詹姆斯.
Oh, James.
我不知道买什么尺寸的.
l didn't know what size to get.
那珠宝店的售货女孩
只有一双大手.
And the girl at the jewelry store
had these really big hands.
但我敢打赌...
But l'll bet...
Perfect.
绝配.
詹姆斯.
James.
我只是觉得
我们应该永远在一起.
l just think we should
be together all the time.
真的?
Really?
如果你愿意.
lf that's okay with you.
正是我的理想.
lt's perfect.
这是什么鸟
下的蛋啊?
Whatever fowl
did you take these eggs from?
你是想说很难吃是吧?
Are we saying we don't like it?
l'm afraid l'm gonna
run into a thumbtack.
怎么，
我这么快就成眼中钉了.
Mother, can't you ever say
anything nice?
妈妈, 难道你就
不能说点好听的吗?
我已经很努力了.
我已经很努力了
l've tried so hard.
l try so hard,
and nothing is good enough for you.
没有任何事合你意的.
我自己来更正一下, 应该是没有一件
我做的事合你心意的.
Let me correct myself, nothing l do
is ever good enough for you.
唔, 没有啊.
这菜牌就做的不错.
Well, that's not true.
The menus are very presentable.
哎呀, 我开玩笑的啦.
Oh, l'm joking.
Honestly,
let me make a suggestion.
说真的,
我给点建议吧.
lf you wanna serve
a truly memorable omelet
如果你做好一份
真正让人难忘的煎蛋卷
试试加点纯小牛肉肠
和羊肚菌菇.
try white veal sausage
and morel mushrooms.
谢了. 我会去挑选蘑菇的.
Thanks. l'll go pick the mushrooms.
你刚说什么来着?
What did you say?
Nothing.
没说什么.
你好, 唐娜.
Hello, Donna.
你好, 詹姆斯.
Hello, James.
你刚在说什么?
What did you say?
- 法文啊.
- 我知道是法文, 告诉我.
- lt's French.
- l know it is, tell me.
Donna, what's the big deal?
唐娜, 这么紧张干嘛呀?
You know Mrs. Tremond?
你认识屈梦太太吗?
- 什么小姐?
- 屈梦太太.
- Miss who?
- Mrs. Tremond.
她孙子在玩魔术时.
跟我讲过这句话.
Her grandson does the magic tricks.
He told me this.
但这是史密斯先生说的.
But it was Mr. Smith.
- Harold?
- He left a suicide note.
- 哈罗德?
- 是他的遗言.
你知道, 它意思是,
"我是一个寂寞的灵魂."
You know, it means,
''l am a lonely soul.''
l have to find Agent Cooper.
我得去找库珀探员.
Donna, what's going on?
唐娜, 到底怎么了?
Hey.
嘿.
Mrs. Tremond's the one
who told me about Harold Smith.
就是屈梦太太
告诉我关于哈罗德·史密斯的事.
She has a grandson
and he said this to me.
她有个孙子
就是他告诉我那法文的.
The same words that are in
Harold Smith's suicide note.
和哈罗德·史密斯的遗言
一模一样.
大概那个男孩
跟哈罗德说过同样的话.
Maybe the boy
said the same thing to Harold.
No, Harold's world was in his words.
不, 他说的就是哈罗德的世界.
那个遗言在透露
一个信息.
The suicide note has to be
a message.
把我们带回到这里来.
lt all leads back here.
She's pretty old. lt might take a second
if her grandson isn't here.
她年级很大了. 如果她孙子不在
那就得等很久门才会开.
- May l help you?
- ls Mrs. Tremond home?
- 有什么事吗?
- 屈梦太太在吗?
我就是.
l'm Mrs. Tremond.
我是说
你妈妈.
lt must have been your mother
l spoke to.
My mother?
She passed away three years ago.
我妈?
她3年前就死了.
l live here alone, honey.
我现在这里一个人住, 宝贝儿.
No, she was here. l spoke to her.
And her grandson, he was here too.
不, 她在这儿住过. 我和她说过话.
还有她孙子, 他当时也在的.
但我没有小孩啊.
But l have no children.
但他当时真的在啊.
他们2个都在的.
But he was here.
They both were.
唐娜, 我们还是走吧.
Donna, we'd better go.
Donna?
Are you Donna Hayward?
唐娜?
你是唐娜·海沃德?
- Yeah.
- Just a moment.
- 是的.
- 请稍等.
l've never seen her before in my life.
我之前从来没见过她.
l thought you delivered meals here.
我想你是送餐来这儿的.
哈罗德死的第二天早上,
我在信箱里发现了这个.
The morning after poor Harold died,
l found this in my mail.
我把它拿出来了.
l meant to turn it in.
lt's for you.
是给你的.
Thank you.
谢谢你.
- lt's Harold's handwriting.
- Open it, Donna.
- 是哈罗德的笔迹.
- 打开它, 唐娜.
lt's Laura's diary,
a page from her diary.
是劳拉的日记,
其中的一页.
Read it.
读来听听.
"2月22日.
''February 22nd.
我昨晚做了个
极奇怪的梦.
Last night l had
the strangest dream.
l was in a red room
with a small man dressed in red
我和一个穿红衣的小人
在一个红色的房间里
一个老男人坐在椅子上.
and an old man sitting in a chair.
我试图和他说话.
l tried to talk to him.
l wanted to tell him who Bob is
because l thought he could help me.
我想告诉他谁是鲍勃
因为我觉得他能救我.
My words came out slow and odd.
但我说话的语调变得又慢又古怪.
lt was frustrating trying to talk.
越使劲去说就越令人感到沮丧.
l got up and walked to the old man.
我站起来走向那个老男人.
然后我弯腰在他耳边
悄悄把秘密告诉了他.
Then l leaned over and whispered
the secret in his ear.
必须有人去制止鲍勃.
Somebody has to stop Bob.
Bob's only afraid of one man,
he told me once.
鲍勃只害怕一个人,
他和我说过一次.
那个人叫迈克.
A man named Mike.
l wonder if this was Mike
in my dream.
我在想我梦中的这人
是不是迈克.
Even if it was only a dream,
l hope he heard me.
就算这只是一个梦,
我也希望他能听见我.
No one in the real world
would believe me.
在现实世界
没有一个人相信我.
February 23rd.
2月23日.
Tonight is the night that l die.
今晚就是我的死期了.
l know l have to
because it's the only way
我知道我必死无疑
因为这是我唯一
to keep Bob away from me.
远离鲍勃的方式.
The only way to tear him out
from inside.
也是唯一从内心将他
撕毁的方法.
我知道他要的是我,
我能感觉到他的欲火.
l know he wants me,
l can feel his fire.
But if l die,
he can't hurt me anymore.''
但只有我死了,
他就再也不能伤害我了."
劳拉和我都做个相同的梦.
Laura and l had the same dream.
- That's impossible.
- Yes, it is.
- 那不可能.
- 是的, 真的.
Deputy, take Donna home.
副警官, 送唐娜回家吧.
l got to see Gerard.
我要去看看杰勒德了.
他已经完全脱水了.
He's completely dehydrated.
他的呼吸越来越困难
他需要药.
His breathing is becoming
more difficult. He needs that drug.
迈克.
迈克, 和我说话.
Mike.
Mike, l need you to talk to me.
- Any longer could kill him.
- Mike.
- 再拖下去会要了他的命.
- 迈克.
Bob has killed again.
鲍勃又杀人了.
l need to know something.
l need you to help me.
有些事我必须知道.
我需要你的帮助.
Bob was in my dream, Laura Palmer
was in my dream, so were you.
我梦见过鲍勃,
劳拉·帕尔默，还有你.
And Laura dreamt about me
the night before she died.
而劳拉死的前一晚
也梦见了我.
The same dream that l had.
和我一样的梦.
l need to unlock that.
l need-- The answer is inside of me.
我必须要解开它.
我必须-- 答案就在我的内心深处.
Bob and l,
when we were killing together,
鲍勃和我,
我们以前一起杀人的时候,
there was this perfect relationship,
是最佳伙伴,
appetite,
欲望,
满足,
satisfaction,
一个金色的圆圈.
a golden circle.
A golden circle.
A ring.
是戒指.
My ring.
我的戒指.
l gave my ring to the Giant.
我把我的戒指给了那个巨人.
He is known to us here.
我们知道他在这儿.
Then he's real?
那么他是真实的?
As real as l.
就我和一样真实.
He can help you find Bob.
他能帮你找到鲍勃.
- How?
- You must ask him first.
- 怎么找?
- 你必须要先问他.
How do l do that?
那我要怎么做呢?
Oh, you have all the clues you need.
哦,你需要的所有线索都已经有了 .
The answer is not here my friend.
我的朋友，答案并不在这里.
The answer is here.
而是在这里.
l don't understand.
我不明白.
太多太多责任了.
So much responsibility.
我知道你.
l know about you.
That milk will cool down on you
你让牛奶凉了
but it's getting warmer now.
但是它现在又渐渐回温了.
''Getting warmer now.''
"现在又渐渐回温了."
Box and tag everything
in these drawers. Everything.
我要你把这抽屉里的所有东西
都贴上标签. 所有东西.
Coop, we found his telephone records.
Look at this.
库, 我们找到了这个通话记录.
看看这个.
The night Laura died.
Telephone call Leland told us about.
劳拉死的那晚.
这就是利兰跟我们提起的那个电话.
Ben called her number
from this office.
本在办公室这儿
打电话给她.
White fox.
白狐貍.
Yeah, white, dead and stuffed.
Maddy was here.
是啊, 白色, 标本和填塞物.
马蒂来过这儿.
我认为本是在办公室这里杀了她
然后再运到瀑布那里的.
l think Ben killed her in this office,
then took her to the waterfall.
He killed Laura
and he killed Maddy.
他杀了劳拉
和马蒂.
Madeleine Ferguson died
the night before last
马德琳·弗格逊是
前晚遇害的
between 1 0 p.m. and midnight.
在10点和子夜之间.
That fits. We didn't take Ben in
until after midnight.
完全吻合. 我们是在子夜之后
才把本抓进去的.
That's as close as l can cut it.
那已经足够我把它打断了.
Ben Horne's blood test.
本·荷恩的血液检验报告.
A couple of minutes,
l'll have this up to code.
2分钟就好了,
我很快会把它们编好码.
Tweaking the sensors, mostly.
把传感器拼好, 差不多了.
Don't want your sprinklers
to be overly jumpy.
别指望你这个灭火洒水头
会自己灵敏的反应.
Gotta set it just so.
必须进行设置才行的.
l wanna talk about my child,
our baby.
我想谈谈关于我孩子的事,
我们的宝宝.
- Maybe.
- Maybe what?
- 也许吧.
- 也许什么啊?
Maybe it is our baby
and maybe it isn't.
也许是我们的孩子
也许不是.
Dick?
基巴吗?
Oh, my Lord, is he the father?
噢, 我的主啊, 他是爸爸吗?
At first l thought
you were the father.
刚开始我以为
你是爸爸.
But then you said
you didn't have any sperms.
但然后你说
你都没有任何精子.
Then l thought it was Dick
but now you say your sperms are back.
之后我就想是基巴的
但现在你说你的精子又回来了.
So as far as l can tell,
it's a 50-50 proposition.
那么我最多只能说,
你们各占50%的机会.
Andy, where are you going?
安迪, 你去哪儿?
What are you doing?
你要干什么?
Who are you calling?
你在给谁打电话?
l want to speak to Richard Tremayne,
Men's Fashions.
我找理查·屈梅恩,
男装部的.
好的, I我等着.
Yes, l'll hold.
你不会伤害他吧, 你会吗, 安迪?
You won't hurt him, will you, Andy?
Tremayne, Brennan.
Andy Brennan.
屈梅恩, 布伦南.
安迪·布伦南.
We need to talk.
我们必须谈谈.
That is, if you're not too busy.
那是, 如果你不太忙的话.
Tojamura-san.
托吉麻辣先生.
真高兴你来电问候.
How nice of you to come calling.
You are in prison.
你坐牢了.
Yes, well,
是啊, 嗯,
a momentary inconvenience,
l assure you.
只是个暂时的困境,
我向你保证.
We have papers to sign.
我们有文件要签署.
The Ghostwood contracts.
格斯伍的合约.
Tojamura-san,
托吉麻辣先生,
l'm afraid there has been a snag.
我恐怕现在有了点小小的障碍.
A snag?
障碍?
Unforeseen difficulties.
Some legal in nature, others...
意料之外的问题.
一些相关法律, 还有其他什么的...
l'm unable to sign
the Ghostwood agreement at this time.
我不能在这个时候
签格斯伍协议书.
Then you will return
my five million dollars.
那么你要退还我
5百万美元.
啊, 我也想把钱退还给你.
Well, l want to return your money.
我也想签合约.
l want to sign the contracts.
Tojamura-san,
托吉麻辣先生,
as you can see,
正如你所见的,
l am incarcerated.
我现在被囚禁了.
Falsely accused,
被人诬告了,
but my brother, the boy genius,
但我弟弟, 绝顶聪明的家伙,
is out looking for a better lawyer.
正在为我找更好的律师.
And until justice is done,
然后只要审判一结束,
until l am able to breathe the air
that free men breathe,
我就能够从新呼吸
自由人的空气了,
l plead with you for understanding.
我恳求你能理解.
This is the long, dark night
of my soul.
这是我灵魂中
黑暗而漫长的一夜.
Time to seek that...
是时候在黑夜里...
...tiny flickering flame within.
...去寻找那点点忽闪而微弱的火焰了.
Forgive me,
l've been very emotional lately.
原谅我吧,
我最近非常情绪化.
Catherine?
凯萨琳?
Benjamin Horne.
本杰明·荷恩.
You're a slimy rat bastard.
你可真是个油嘴滑舌的卑鄙小人，混帐家伙.
And l intend to make whatever
remains of your pathetic existence
但无论如何，我还是打算
保住你这条贱命
好让你继续存在于这个人间地狱.
a living hell.
Oh, Catherine.
啊, 凯萨琳.
Oh, my God.
噢, 我的神啊.
You've come.
你终于来了.
Oh, Catherine.
噢, 凯萨琳.
Catherine, Catherine,
tell Sheriff Truman
凯萨琳, 凯萨琳,
快去告诉杜鲁门警长
about the night
that we spent together
那晚
我们是一起过的
the night that Laura was killed.
劳拉被杀的那晚.
You want me to beg?
你想要我乞求吗?
Because l'll beg.
因为我会的.
Will you sign Ghostwood
and the mill over to me?
你会把格斯伍和锯木厂
签回给我吗?
ln a heartbeat.
立刻签.
Clever disguise, Catherine.
你的易容术很聪明, 凯萨琳.
Really brilliant.
实在是太有才华了.
Signed, sealed
签字, 盖印
and delivered.
送达.
Now, you'll tell the sheriff, huh?
现在, 你会去告诉杜鲁门警长了吗, 嗯?
You'll tell the sheriff.
你会告诉警长的.
l'll consider it.
我会考虑的.
Catherine. Catherine, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
凯萨琳. 凯萨琳, 等会儿.
等等.
lt's the truth, after all.
毕竟, 那是事实啊.
Why, Ben, we've spent our entire
adult lives lying to each other.
为什么呀, 本, 我们都已经花了
一生去彼此欺骗.
Why spoil it with the truth now?
犯得着在这会儿以真相来破坏气氛吗?
Catherine.
凯萨琳.
Catherine!
凯萨琳!
Donna,
唐娜,
l'm so happy you stopped by.
你来拜访我真高兴.
We haven't had the time
to just sit down and talk for so long.
我们好久都没
坐下来仔细聊过了.
May l get you a glass of lemonade?
我给你倒杯柠檬水怎样?
不了, 谢了, 帕尔默先生.
我马上要走了.
No, thanks, Mr. Palmer.
l only have a minute.
This is for Maddy. lt's a tape
of a song we did with James.
这是给马蒂的. 是一盘我们
和詹姆斯一起录的歌.
l want her to have a copy.
我复制了一份给她.
That's very sweet of you.
你太贴心了.
She told me all about this.
她和我讲过这事儿.
She said it was
a very enjoyable experience.
她说那是个
非常好玩的体验.
Anyway, if you could mail it to her,
l'd really appreciate it.
总之, 如果你能寄给她的话,
我就真的很感激了.
No, it won't be any problem at all.
没事, 一点问题也没有.
ls something wrong?
有什么不妥吗?
No.
没有.
Those glasses.
那副太阳镜.
They were Laura's.
Maddy gave them to me.
是劳拉的.
马蒂把它给了我.
l thought they looked familiar.
我就觉得看起来眼熟.
Mr. Palmer,
帕尔默先生,
did you know
that they found Laura's secret diary?
你知道他们
找到了劳拉的秘密日记吗?
Diary? Yes,
they took it from her room.
日记? 知道,
他们是从她房间拿走的.
No, not the one the police found.
不, 不是警察拿走的那本.
She had another one.
她还有另外一本.
l didn't even know about it,
did you?
连我都不知道,
你呢?
No.
不知道.
She gave it to a man
named Harold Smith.
她给了一个叫
哈罗德·史密斯的人.
Harold killed himself a few days ago.
哈罗德几天前自杀死了.
The police found it in his apartment.
警察在他的公寓里找到了它.
Oh, my God.
噢, 我的天啊.
l had no idea.
我一点儿也不知道.
l wish l knew what was in it,
don't you?
我真想知道里面写了什么,
你说呢?
l think about Laura all the time.
我整天想起劳拉.
Oh, excuse me.
哦, 失陪了.
Hello?
喂?
Yeah, Beth, how are you?
是你, 贝丝, 怎么样?
No, not since yesterday.
没有, 从昨天起.
Of course, Beth. l took Maddy
to the bus station myself.
肯定, 贝丝. 是我亲自
送马蒂去车站的.
Well, l--
那好, 我--
l'm sure there must be some
perfectly reasonable explanation.
我想她肯定
有什么别的事要去办吧.
Yes, of course.
l'll call you immediately,
是, 好的.
我会及时给你打电话的,
within the hour.
一小时内.
Bye, Beth.
再见, 贝丝.
Maddy?
马蒂吗?
lt's the strangest thing.
真是怪事了.
She never made it home.
她一直没有回家.
Oh, God.
噢, 天啊.
Donna, don't you worry
about a thing.
唐娜, 你不是
很焦虑吗.
l'll get us some lemonade
我去倒点柠檬水来
and we'll sit down
and give it a think
然后坐下来
好好思量一下
and we'll work the problem out.
再一起把问题给解决掉.
Together.
一起解决掉.
l knew she was expecting us,
l mean--
我明白她是希望我们,
我意思是--
l guess l was selfish.
l thought l could see her anytime.
我想我很自私.
我以为我能随时见到她.
Missoula's not that far away, right?
密苏拉离这儿不远吧?
Donna, you're taking this much
too much to heart.
唐娜, 你想这个想太多了
别胡思乱想了.
l'm sure she's just fine.
我肯定她平安无事的.
l know the cure for what ails you.
我知道怎样去安抚你内心的苦闷.
lt's simple, really.
很简单, 真的.
lt always makes me feel good.
它总是能让我心情好起来.
May we have this dance...
我们来跳这个舞吧...
...please?
...请?
You stay right there.
你留在那儿.
Harry?
哈里?
Leland, we need your help.
利兰, 我们需要你的协助.
What is it?
是什么呢?
- There's been another murder.
- Oh, my God.
- 又发生了一起凶杀案.
- 噢, 我的天啊.
l can't tell you why or how but we need
your help and we need it right away.
我也不知道该怎样说才好
反正我们需要你的协助，马上.
All right, anything, certainly.
Let me get my coat.
好的, 这个当然, 没问题的.
我去拿大衣.
Maddy.
马蒂.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
怎么回事?
发生什么事了?
- lt's Maddy.
- What about her?
- 是马蒂.
- 她怎么了?
She's dead.
她死了.
lt was the same killer.
The same one who killed Laura.
是同一个凶手.
杀害劳拉的同一个凶手.
l heard Mr. Palmer get a phone call
from her mother.
我听见帕尔默先生
和她妈妈在讲电话.
She said
she hadn't gotten home yet.
她说
她还没回到家.
Then they came over to talk to him,
Sheriff Truman.
然后他们就来找他了,
杜鲁门警长.
- We could've helped her.
- How?
- 我们本来可以救她的.
- 怎么救?
- We could've helped her.
- How?
- 我们本来可以救她的.
- 怎么救?
l don't know.
我不知道.
- This is no good.
- What do you mean?
- 这样不好.
- 你是指什么?
You mean us?
我们么?
- l gotta go.
- James, it's not our fault, don't leave.
- 我得走了.
- 詹姆斯, 那不是我们的错, 别走.
lt doesn't matter, don't you see?
已经不重要了, 难道你还不懂吗?
Nothing we do matters.
Nothing's ever gonna change.
不过我们做什么.
都不会改变命运.
lt doesn't matter if we're happy
and the rest of the world goes to hell.
我们快乐与否，或世界末日
都无关紧要了.
James, don't leave.
詹姆斯, 别走.
James, don't leave me!
詹姆斯, 不要离开我!
Harry.
哈里.
Leland.
利兰.
Why are we here, Agent Cooper?
我们为什么在这儿, 库珀探员?
ls someone meeting us?
我们要见什么人吗?
Yes.
是的.
ls it the killer?
见凶手?
l don't know. Maybe.
我不知道. 也许吧.
Ed, glad you're here.
艾德, 很高兴你来了.
l need everyone's help
to clear the room.
我需要大家帮忙
整理一下这个空间.
l need a large space in the center.
在房的中间留出一块大空地.
Of course.
好的.
Hail, hail. The gang's all here.
欢迎, 欢迎. 大伙儿都到齐了.
Bobby, why don't you wheel Leo
back over there.
波比, 你干嘛不把里欧
推到那边去呢.
Stay very, very quiet, you read me?
非常非常安静的, 在那边呆着, 听懂了吗?
Give yourself a raise, Hawk.
你可以一边玩去了, 豪克.
Gentlemen, two days ago
a young woman was found murdered
先生们, 2天前
一位年轻的女士被人谋杀了
by the same individual,
l believe, responsible
我相信,
是杀害劳拉·帕尔默的
for the death of Laura Palmer.
同一个人干的.
l have reason to believe
that the killer is in this room.
我还有理由相信这个凶手
就在这间房子里.
As a member of the Bureau,
l spend most of my time
作为警方的一份子,
我花了大量时间
seeking simple answers
to difficult questions.
在错综复杂的问题中
寻找答案.
ln the pursuit of Laura's killer,
l have employed Bureau guidelines,
在追查杀劳拉的凶手时,
我除了按规章办事,
deductive technique,
Tibetan method, instinct and luck.
使用推理技术,
还有藏民的方法, 也依靠直觉和运气.
But now l find myself
in need of something new,
但现在我发现自己
的确需要求助于新事物了,
which for lack of a better word
we shall call ''magic.''
没有什么比我们用『魔术』
这个词更贴切了."
Would you like us to hum?
你需要我们唸唸有词吗?
A Tibetan chant, perhaps.
搞不好是首藏族圣诗呢.
l think it's going terrifically well,
don't you?
我倒觉得形势大好啊,
你觉得呢?
Now what?
那现在干嘛?
Harry, l'm not completely sure.
哈里, 我不完全肯定.
Someone is missing.
还有一个人没到.
Excuse us.
抱歉我们来晚了.
Major Briggs, right on time.
布里格斯少校, 来的正好.
l was on my way home.
我正开车回家.
This kind gentleman
flagged me down,
这位好好先生
把我截停了,
asked if l could drive him here.
请我送他到这来.
l know that gum.
l used to chew it when l was a kid.
我知道这口香糖.
我小的时候吃过.
That's my most favorite gum
in the world.
是这个世界上我最喜欢
的口香糖.
That gum you like
is going to come back in style.
它的口味
始终如一.
My father
是我父亲
killed me.
杀了我.
Ben Horne,
本·荷恩,
l would like you to accompany me
to the sheriff's station.
我想你陪我
一同会警局.
You might like to bring along
Leland Palmer as your attorney.
你可以带上利兰·帕尔默一同
作为你的律师.
Let's take him down to interrogation.
把他带到审讯室.
Agent Cooper,
is he going to be charged?
库珀探员,
他会被起诉吗?
Yes.
是的.
Then l think l'd like to begin bail
proceedings as soon as possible.
那我想我还是尽快
开始准备保释程序.
He'll have his day in court.
他很快就要上法庭了.
Harry.
哈里.
Everything will be all right, Ben.
会没事的, 本.
Hawk, take Ben upstairs
and release him.
豪克, 带本上楼
释放他吧.
- Leland?
- That's not Leland.
- 利兰?
- 那个已经不是利兰了.
How did you know?
你是怎么知道的?
Laura told me in her dream.
劳拉在梦中告诉我的.
We're gonna need
a lot stronger evidence than this.
我们必须
要找到更多有力的证据.
How about a confession, Harry?
让他自招怎样, 哈里?
You have the right to an attorney.
你有权请律师.
lf you cannot afford an attorney,
one will be appointed for you.
如果你支付不起律师,
我们将会为你指定一名.
Oh, yeah. l suppose you wanna
ask him some questions, huh?
噢, 对了. 我猜你肯定
有问题问他, 哼?
Did you kill Laura Palmer?
是你杀了劳拉·帕尔默?
That's a yes.
那是『是』的意思.
How about Madeleine Ferguson?
那马德琳·弗格逊呢?
- What do you think?
- l'm asking you.
- 你觉得呢?
- 我在问你呢.
- What do you think?
- Answer the question.
- 你觉得呢?
- 回答问题.
Oh, gosh, gee, gee whiz.
l guess l kind of sort of did.
哦, 糟了, 哇, 妈妈呀.
我想或许大概是我干的吧.
l have this thing for knives.
你可是有把柄在我手上啊.
Just like what happened to you
in Pittsburgh that time.
就像你上次
在匹兹堡发生的那样.
Huh, Cooper?
哼, 库珀?
Oh, Leland.
噢, 利兰.
Leland, Leland.
利兰, 利兰.
You've been a good vehicle
你一直都是辆好车
and l've enjoyed the ride.
我可享受开着你到处跑了.
But now he's weak and full of holes.
但他现在已经满目疮痍，也废了.
lt's almost nearly time
to shuffle off to Buffalo.
也差不多是时候
把他扔到水牛城了.
Does Leland know
what you've done?
利兰知道
你所做的一切吗?
Leland's a babe in the woods
利兰不过是个幼稚无知的人
with a large hole
where his conscience used to be.
他身上有个大洞
曾经装着他的良心.
And when l go, children,
l will pull that ripcord
当我进去后, 我的儿啊,
我就把它封锁了
and you watch Leland, remember.
Watch him.
你给我走着瞧，利兰, 记住.
小心点.
But not for long.
不用太久.
That's enough for me.
足够证据了.
Dick,
基巴,
could you come with me, please?
能跟我来一下吗, 这边请?
Okay, here's how
this is going to work.
好了, 现在
给我听着.
l'm going to keep my baby.
我打算要这个孩子.
That's not open for discussion.
没有任何商量的余地.
- l see.
- Be quiet, let her talk.
- 我知道.
- 安静点, 让他说完.
Got a light?
诱火吗?
No.
没有.
You were saying.
我看到了.
There's only one way to handle this.
只有一个办法去处理这件事.
They have a test to determine
the blood type of the father.
他们会通过血型测试
来最后决定谁是爸爸.
lt could be you
那可能是你
or it could be you.
也有可你能是你.
They won't be doing this test
until after the baby is born,
但是必须等宝宝出生后
他们才会进行测试,
during which time
l expect complete cooperation
在宝宝出生之前的这段时间
我希望你们2位先生
from each of you two gentlemen.
能充分配合.
Whatever you say, Lucy.
不管怎么说, 露西.
l mean, it is your baby.
我是说, 反正是你的孩子.
Thank you.
谢谢你.
Ben Horne's blood test,
he's the wrong type.
本·荷恩的血液测试说明,
他的血型不吻合.
Harry, the answer was right in front
of me from the very beginning.
哈里, 答案其实一开始
就已经在我眼前了.
What did the little man do
in my dream?
还记得那个小侏儒在我梦里
干什么吗?
He danced.
他在跳舞.
After Laura's death,
Leland danced compulsively.
劳拉死后,
利兰就开始强迫性的跳舞.
We were told that Bob the killer
was a gray-haired man.
它还预示我们
那个叫鲍勃的凶手有一头灰发.
When Leland killed Jacques,
his hair turned gray overnight.
当利兰杀了雅克后,
他就一夜灰头了.
Leland said when he was a child
利兰说他小时候
the gray-haired man next door
was named Robertson.
那个住他隔壁的灰发人
叫罗伯逊.
Mike said the people Bob inhabited
were his children.
迈克则说鲍勃所寄生的那个肉身
就是他的孩子.
Robertson, son of Robert.
罗伯的儿子，罗伯逊.
The letters under the finger nails:
R, O, B, T.
那些在指甲下的字母:
Bob was spelling his name.
鲍勃在拼自己的名字.
A signature on a demon self-portrait.
签名是魔鬼的自述.
Why would he kill her?
那他为什么要杀她?
Laura was writing about Bob
in her diary.
劳拉在她的日记里
写下了关于鲍勃的事.
Leland found it, ripped out the pages.
She knew he was on to her.
利兰发现了, 并把那几页撕了下来.
她就知道被盯上了.
lt was Leland who placed that call
from Ben Horne's office
劳拉死那晚接到的电话
就是利兰在
to Laura the night she died.
本·荷恩办公室打出去的.
He was the third man
outside Jacques' cabin.
那晚，站在雅克小木屋窗外
的神秘人，就是他.
He took the girls to the train car. lt was
his blood we found not Ben Horne's.
是他把女孩们绑架到火车厢那里.
案发现场的血迹是他的，而不是本·荷恩的.
- Then why kill Maddy?
- Maybe she reminded him of Laura.
- 那为什么还要杀马蒂?
- 或许她令他想起了劳拉.
Maddy was going home.
He couldn't bear to part with her.
马蒂要回家了.
他不能承受和她分开的事实.
He wanted to relive the experience
他想在次重温杀戮的体验
or maybe she realized
Bob was the killer and he found out.
又或许是她意识到鲍勃
就是凶手，然后被他发现了.
Now, this Bob.
但现在, 这个鲍勃.
He can't really exist.
l mean, Leland is just crazy, right?
他不能真的存在.
我是说, 只能说利兰疯了, 不是吗?
Through the dark of futures past,
穿越未来过去的黑暗,
the magician longs to see
魔术师渴望见到
One chants out between two worlds
在2个世界之间传出的1首圣歌
Fire walk with me
与火同行
l'll catch you with my death bag.
我会把你抓进我的死亡之袋.
You may think l've gone insane
你以为我发疯了
but l promise l will kill again!
但我保证我会再开杀戒!
Harry, hurry.
哈里, 快来.
The key.
钥匙.
Leland.
利兰.
Harry. Leland.
哈里. 利兰.
Call an ambulance.
快叫救护车.
Oh, God, Laura.
噢, 天啊, 劳拉.
l killed her.
是我杀了她.
Oh, my God. l killed my daughter.
啊, 我的天啊. 我杀了我的女儿.
l didn't know.
我还蒙在鼓里.
Laura, forgive me.
劳拉, 宽恕我吧.
Forgive me.
宽恕我吧.
- Oh, God.
- lt's okay.
- 啊, 天啊.
- 好了.
lt's all right.
没事的.
l was just a boy.
那时我还是个小孩.
l saw him in my dreams.
我在梦里见到了他.
He said he wanted to play.
他说他想和我玩.
He opened me and l invited him
and he came inside me.
他把我打开了，而我也邀请他了
他就这样侵占了我的内心.
He went inside?
他进去了?
When he was inside, l didn't know.
当他来的时候, 我察觉不到.
And when he was gone,
l couldn't remember.
当他走了,
我也什么都不记得了.
He made me do things...
他控制了我，去做那些...
...terrible things.
...那些可怕的事情.
He said he wanted lives,
他说他想要生命,
he wanted others.
别人的生命.
Others that they could use
like they used me.
任意去使用别人的生命
就像现在用我的一样.
Like Laura?
就像劳拉?
They wanted her.
他们要她.
They wanted Laura,
but she was strong.
他们要劳拉,
但她很坚强.
She fought them.
她反抗他们.
She wouldn't let them in.
她不让他们侵占她的肉身.
Oh, God.
啊, 上帝啊.
They had me kill that girl, Theresa.
是他们让我杀了那个女孩的, 杜丽莎.
And they-- They said...
他们-- 他们还说...
...if l didn't give them Laura,
...如果我不把劳拉给他们,
they'd have me kill her too.
他们也会控制我杀了她.
But she wouldn't let them in?
但她不会让他们侵占的?
She said she'd die
before she let them.
她说她宁愿死
也不愿意给他们侵占.
And they made me kill her.
然后他们就要我杀了她.
Oh, God, have mercy on me.
噢, 上帝啊, 可怜可怜我吧.
What have l done?
看我都做了什么?
看我都做了什么啊?
Oh, God, l love her.
啊, 天啊, 我是爱她的.
l loved her with all my heart.
我全心全意的爱着她.
My angel, forgive me.
我的天使, 宽恕我吧.
Leland.
利兰.
Leland, the time has come
for you to seek the path.
利兰, 时间会为你
寻求解脱之路.
Your soul has set you
face to face with a clear light
你的灵魂以明灯
引领你直面一切
and you are now about to experience it
in its reality,
现在进入它的世界
去好好体验吧,
wherein all things are like the void
and cloudless sky
里面空无一人
万里无云
and the naked, spotless intellect
is like a transparent vacuum
赤裸裸一望无际, 圣洁无暇的灵悟
犹如真空般清澈透明
without circumference or center.
无始无终.
Leland, in this moment,
know yourself
利兰, 这一刻,
感悟你自己
and abide in that state.
并坚持着那种状态.
Look to the light, Leland.
注视那盏明灯, 利兰.
Find the light.
找到它.
l see it.
我看到它了.
lnto the light, Leland.
lnto the light.
在BE436A06里面, 利兰.
在BE436A06里.
l see her.
我看到她了.
She's there.
她在那里.
lnto the light, Leland.
在36F55044里, 利兰.
She's beautiful.
她美丽极了.
lnto the light.
在55F791D8里.
Laura.
劳拉.
Don't be afraid.
别害怕.
He was completely insane.
他完全精神错乱了.
Think so?
真这么想吗?
But people saw Bob.
但大家都看到鲍勃了.
People saw him in visions:
Laura, Maddy, Sarah Palmer.
她们都确实看见过他:
劳拉, 马蒂, 莎拉·帕尔默.
Gentlemen,
there's more in heaven and earth...
先生们,
其实这更像是我们以自己的哲学世界观...
...than is dreamt up in our philosophy.
...在天地间虚构出来的东西.
Amen.
阿门.
Well, l've lived in these old woods
most of my life.
啊, 我几乎在这老森林里
渡过了大半生.
l've seen some strange things
but this is way off the map.
我也见过一些奇怪的事
但这次简直超乎想像.
l'm having a hard time believing.
实在无法理解.
Harry, is it easier to believe
哈里, 如果只是解释为一个男人
a man would rape and murder
his own daughter?
强奸和谋杀了自己的亲生女儿
是不是更容易理解呢?
Any more comforting?
使人更易接受呢?
No.
不.
An evil that great
in this beautiful world...
这个美丽的世界
充满了邪恶...
...finally,
does it matter what the cause?
...以致最后,
原因是什么已经不重要了?
Yes, because it's our job to stop it.
是的, 因为我们的工作就是警恶除奸.
Yeah.
是啊.
Maybe that's all Bob is.
也许那就是鲍勃吧.
The evil that men do.
一种引诱人犯罪的邪恶力量.
Maybe it doesn't matter
what we call it.
我们称它做什么
也不重要了.
Maybe not.
也不一定.
But if he was real, if he was here,
但如果他是真实的呢, 如果他真的存在过呢,
and we had him trapped
我们逮到过他
and he got away,
只是又让他给逃了,
where's Bob now?
鲍勃现在在哪儿呢?